CHUMA MQEKE

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+27 607 616 425 | +27 781 554 750

mqekec3@gmail.com

2 10 Afadjato Street, Delft, Cape Town, 7100

linkedin.com/in/chuma-mqeke

PROFILE

An Advanced Diploma in ICT graduate specializing in application development within the IT field, actively seeking for a junior software developer role to enhance my professional growth and contribute to your team's goals and company's vision. I bring a strong background in software development, supported by one year as a system developer and six months as a data analyst. Currently, I am further honing my technical skills through UVU Africa's 18-month Software Development Program.

SKILLS

- HTML and CSS
- JavaScript
- React js
- SQL
- Python
- Java
- Problem-Solving
- · Technical skills
- Communication skills

EDUCATION

ADV DIPLOMA IN ICT: APPLICATIONS DEVEOPMENT

Walter Sisulu University

2021 - 2022

N DIP: INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT)

Walter Sisulu University

2018 - 2020

MATRIC

Gwadana Senior Secondary School

2015 - 2017

EXPERIENCE

SFULL-STACK DEVELOPER INTERN

UVU Africa (Capacity Tech Career Accelerator)

2023 - Present

- Web Development using HTML CSS and JavaScript.
- Manage and track changes in codebase using version control Git
- Work with server-side languages (Node.js) to develop server-side logic.
- Develop RESTful APIs to facilitate communication between frontend and back-end.
- Development of applications using Java and Python.
- Design and implement database structure using SQL and PostgresSQL for efficient data storage and retrieval.

SYSTEM DEVELOPER INTERN

Afrocentric IP

2022/07 - 2023/06

- System support
- Data clean-up
- System testing

DATA ANALYST INTERN

Department of Education 2021/11 - 2022/05

- Training schools on SASAMS and LURITS
- Administration, database analysis and Technical support
- Monitor the program and progress of submission on EMIS tools and DDD. Give support to schools and follow up.

REFERENCES

Ms. A Maliwa +27 78 692 2178 UVU Africa
Mr. G Makinana +27 79 077 1591 Afrocentric IP

Ms. N Rhwayi +27 84 555 4559 Department of Education